Let's go back to the problem.
我们再回到问题
We want to track a pedestrian moving in front of our autonomous vehicle.
我们想要追踪在无人车前移动的行人
At its core, the Kalman filter is a two-step estimation problem,
卡尔曼滤波器本质上是一个两步估算问题
predict and then update.
包括预测和更新
We always start with what we already know from the past about the pedestrian.
我们开始时 依赖已知的行人信息
We use that information to predict the state of the pedestrian up to the time
推断出行人在下次测量到达时
when the next measurement arrives, and this is called the prediction step.
的行人状态 这叫做预测步骤
The next step is called the update step, where we essentially use the new
下一步叫更新步骤 其本质是
observations to correct our belief about the state of the pedestrian.
使用新的观察数据纠正我们对于行人状态的信度
The Kalman filter simply consists of an endless loop of prediction/update steps,
卡尔曼滤波器一般是由无穷的预测更新步骤组成的
this is what you built with Sebastian earlier in this module.
你和 Sebastian 之前在本课程创建的滤波器也是这样
But what happens when there are two sensors that observe the same
那么 如果有两个传感器观察同一名
pedestrian?
行人呢
How does that change the Kalman comma filter?
卡尔曼滤波器会发生什么变化？
Actually, we can keep the same processing flow with the difference that
实际上 我们可以使用同样的处理流程 区别在于
each sensor is going to have its own prediction/update scheme.
每个传感器都有独立的预测/更新周期
In other words, the belief about the pedestrian's position and
换句话说 关于行人位置和速度的信度
velocity is updated asynchronously
是非同步更新的
each time new measurement is received regardless the source sensor.
每次收到新测量值后更新 不考虑来自哪个传感器
Let's step through an example flow to see how it works.
我们看一个例子 了解具体情况
Here the pedestrian state at time k is a distribution with
这里显示了在时间 k 的行人状态分布
its mean (x) and covariance (P).
均值为 X 协方差为 P
Let's say we're now at time k + 1, and
假设现在时间到了 K+1
we've just received the laser measurement.
我们刚刚收到一个激光测量值
The first thing we do before we look at the measurement update
在查看测量更新前 我们首先要做的是
is to make a prediction about where we
预测我们认为
think the pedestrian from time k will be at time k+1.
来自时间 K 的行人在 时间 K+1 在哪里
The second thing we do is the so called measurement update, where we
第二件事叫做测量值更新
combine the pedestrian's predicted state with the new laser measurement.
需要综合行人的预测状态和新的激光测量值
What we now have is a more accurate belief about the pedestrian's position
现在 我们对行人在时间 K+1 的位置有了
at time k+1, this is what we call the posterior.
更准确的信仰
Now let's imagine that we receive the radar measurement at time k+2.
假设我们在时间 K+2 收到了雷达测量值
First, we again predict the pedestrian state from k+1 to k+2.
首先 我们再次预测行人从 K+1 到 K+2 的状态
Note, this prediction for
注意 这次雷达预测
radar is exactly the same function as in the laser case.
使用的函数和激光预测一样
What changes, in this case, is the Measurement Update step.
在本例中 不同的地方在于测量更新步骤
As we know, the radar sees the word differently than laser.
我们知道 雷达和激光观察世界的方式不同
While laser provides measurement in a Cartesian coordinate system,
激光提供的测量数据是基于笛卡尔坐标系的
radar provides measurement in a polar coordinate system.
而雷达提供的测量数据是基于极坐标系的
Thus we have to use different measurement update functions specific
因此 我们必须使用专门针对雷达的
to radar data, so this is a more detailed view of the Kalman filter.
不同测量更新函数 因此 这就是通用滤波器的详细结构
We received the measurements from different sensors at each timestamp, and
我们在每个时间戳上收到了来自不同传感器的测量值i
then we make a prediction followed by a measurement update.
然后进行预测 再进行测量值更新
Are you following me so far?
现在都跟得上吗？
In the next quiz, I want you to continue this flow, but
在接下来的小测试中 我希望你能按照这个流程
this time let's think about predicting and updating if data from
但这次我们要考虑的是 在时间 K+3
different sensors arrive simultaneously at time k+3
不同传感器的数据同时到达 如何预测和更新